

# Vancouver, BC, Canada alecng94@gmail.com

alecng.ca • linkedin.com/in/alecng • github.com/alec-ng

## **Professional Summary**

Software engineer with 3.5 years industry experience in web application development, technical architecture, and business consulting. Delivered multiple web portal applications to over 50,000 users as a tech lead responsible for the architecture and development. My expertise lies in combining a technical foundation in full stack engineering with strong client services and interpersonal skills.

### Skills

**Front-End:** ReactJS, ES6 JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Salesforce Aura Components, Lightning Web Components (LWC), Bootstrap, Webpack, Babel, Gulp, Jest, Enzyme

**Back-End:** NoSQL, Relational Database Design, SQL, Salesforce Apex Object Oriented Programming (OOP) Language, Salesforce Object Query Language (SOQL), Google Firebase

**Software Processes:** Git, Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD), Test Driven Development (TDD), Behaviour Driven Development (BDD), Agile Methodology

Consulting: Product Demos, Business Presentations, Requirement Gathering, Training Sessions

## **Work Experience**

#### **Groundswell Cloud Solutions**

Senior Technical Consultant

*Jan 2019 - Oct 2019* 

- Managed a team of 6 as a tech lead in the development and launch of a Salesforce mobile app feature deployed to over 13,000 users
- Led client facing software architecture discussions on security, scalability and data migration strategies for a customer portal to be rolled out to 200,000 users across 3 continents
- Formalized and documented the company's security guidelines for Salesforce development based on OWASP and Salesforce standards

Technical Consultant

Sep 2017 - Jan 2019

- Designed the front end architecture for a customer portal launched to 40,000 active users using Salesforce's Aura Components framework
- Acted as principal consultant for a client by planning future roadmaps, creating statements of work and supporting production issues
- Selectively chosen by Salesforce to present a 20 minute talk at Dreamforce 2018 about JavaScript testing on the Lightning Platform
- Developed a cross-browser, public facing Google Maps application that has logged an average of 8,000 unique searches a day

- Published a Salesforce managed package written in JavaScript and Apex that improves developer productivity by providing dashboard versioning capabilities for the Wave Analytics application
- Supported the development and release of a custom Stripe payment subscription system built on Salesforce to a 300 person user base

### Cardant, formerly Avanti Commerce

.NET Developer Co-op

*May 2015 - Dec 2015* 

- Optimized an internal PDF exporting tool by converting it from a server to client side JavaScript application, achieving a 75% reduction in wait time
- Spearheaded the refactoring of an ASP.NET test suite following Agile methodology, resulting in a 20% increase in code coverage

## **Projects**

### React Library | react-brandywine-editor

Jan 2020

- Published to npm a React based block editor used for creating custom web blogging content
- Features a plugin based design that allows developers to easily extend and customize the editor

### React Application | alecng.ca/blog

Nov 2019

- Designed a portfolio and blogging platform using React and Firebase
- Created a custom CMS system that integrated a Firebase hosted NoSQL database with react-brandywine-editor to power a photo blog

### **Education**

Bachelor of Applied Sciences, Computer Engineering, 2017 University of British Columbia